我们,是水晶
♪ We ♪ are the crystal
战士
♪ gems
我们总能拯救世界
♪ we'll always save the day
如果你认为我们不行
♪ and if you think we can't, ♪
我们总能找到方法
♪ we'll always find a way
这就是为什么这个世界
♪ that's why the people
的人
♪ of this world
相信
♪ believe in
石榴
♪ Garnet
紫晶
♪ Amethyst
和珍珠
♪ and Pearl
和史蒂文!
and Steven!
宝石劫案
出品
UUU字幕组
翻译
presisco
特效
压制
SG
人类动物园,我不敢相信居然还存在
The Human Zoo. I can't believe it still exists.
爸爸肯定在里面
Dad's got to be in there.
我们只要找到他并将他救出来
We just have to find him and bust him out.
那些宝石人
Those Gems.
紫晶守卫
Amethyst guards.
是啊
Right.
好像我们能大摇大摆的走进去
Like we could just waltz up
一个无主的珍珠,一个融合体,
as an ownerless Pearl, a Fusion,
和-和,你
and -- and you.
我们只需要伪装,我就叫"艾斯呆板·宇宙老爹"
We just need disguises. I'll be Esteban Universedad.
Esteban在西班牙语中相当于Stephan,而Universedad则是大学
史蒂文,你的名字并没有用
Steven, it doesn't matter what your name is.
我们太显眼了
We're all going to stand out.
不会
We won't stand out
只要我们的表现与本来的身份一致的话
if we play the roles we were made for.
红宝石!蓝宝石!
Ruby! Sapphire!
好吧,各位,听她的
Okay everybody, hear her out.
今天,我,作为蓝宝石,正在执行公务,伴随我的有红宝石护卫...
Today, I'm a Sapphire traveling with my Ruby guard...
嗯!
Hm!
还有我个人的珍珠
And my personal Pearl.
嗯-哼!
Mm-hmm!
艾斯呆板,我将你作为献给动物园的大礼
Esteban, I've brought you as an offering for the zoo.
"可怜的艾斯呆板啊!"
Pobrecito Esteban!
呃,我呢?
Uh, what about me?
你作为额外打手陪同我
You're accompanying me as extra muscle.
像她们那种?
Muscle like them?
没错
Exactly.
但我从没看见过其他紫晶
But I've never even seen another Amethyst before.
那我做什么?如果我说错话了呢?
What do I do? What if I say something wrong?
看着办吧
Just look the part.
你too young,我们长者
You're new and we're rusty,
我们只用坚持到找到格雷格就行
but we just have to sell this long enough to find Greg.
这真的管用吗?
Is this really going to work?
不
No.
我们得呆在一起,直截了当
Just stick together, play it straight.
让我们改变未来
Let's change the future.
你们永远不可能关住我的,你们这群石头蛋!
You'll never cage me, ya rock heads!
说明来意
State your purpose.
我是来完成动物园的货运任务的
I'm here to make a delivery to the Human Zoo.
坏消息-人类动物园关闭了
Bad news -- the Human Zoo shut down,
也就是意味着我们不得不把你直接扔进太空
which means we'll just have to throw you into space.
哈!看,他居然信了
Ha! Look. It believed me.
你们在干吗?
What are you doing?
没什么,霍利蓝玛瑙
Nothing, Holly Blue Agate.
为什么你不告诉我
Why didn't you tell me
蓝宝石来这里了?
there was a Sapphire here?
你对她说了什么不敬的话吗?
What have you miscreants been saying to them?
没有,长官
Nothing, Holly.
你一定要见谅啊
You'll have to forgive them.
他们来自地球
They're from Earth.
咳!道歉
Ahem! Apologize.
请原谅我们
Forgive us.
嗷!
Ow!
请原谅我们,璧下
Forgive us, Your Clarity.
没必要再揪着旧事不放
No use dwelling on the past.
我为收藏集合带来了一个新的人类
I've brought a new human for the collection.
这多么新奇啊-
How unprecedented --
一千年来什么都出现
nothing for millennia
而现在突然两个人类接踵而至!
and then two humans back-to-back!
也许,这样最好吧
Well, it's probably for the best.
第一个的状态...并不好
That first one wasn't in the...best condition.
爸爸!那是他!
Dad! That's him!
嘘!
Shh!
哦,人类无尽无休的叫唤!他在叫唤什么啊?
Oh, they're incessant barking! What is it saying?
-另一个也很吵
- The other one was loud too.
而且还在不停挣扎
And all that thrashing about.
我很确定蓝钻石愿意亲自表达谢意
I'm sure Blue Diamond will want to thank you personally,
但你刚好错过她了
but you just missed her.
紫晶,带这个人类去-
Amethyst, take this human to the --
等等!
Wait!
有件事,我们走了那么远
The thing is we've traveled so far,
如果就这么离开实在是可惜
and it would be a shame to leave so quickly.
也许你能带我们参观一下设施?
Perhaps you'd grant us a tour of the facility?
我非常荣幸
I would be honored.
来这里,伟大的璧下
Right this way, Your Grand Clarity.
紫晶得留在这里看门
Amethysts are to stay and guard the door.
呃,但...
Uh, but...
大门
The door.
你的珍珠总是与您肩并肩行走吗?
Does your Pearl always walk next to you?
我在这就好
I'll just be right here.
嗯,很贫嘛
Hmm. Chatty.
此设施原来属于粉钻石
This facility originally belonged to Pink Diamond
收留并任用本来毫无用处的石英们
and houses and staffs the otherwise useless Quartzes
那些石英制造于她的殖民地
she produced on what was her colony.
但蓝钻石与她值得信赖的玛瑙-
But Blue Diamond and her trusted Agate --
也就是我-
that's me --
自第二代的曙光后一直在维护这个地方
have been maintaining this place since the dawn of Era 2.
是她要做什么,还是我要先说什么?
Is she going to do it, or should I say something?
哦
Oh.
珍珠,门
Pearl, the door.
嗯?噢!
Hm? Oh!
好,好
Right, right.
我知道了
I got it.
你对她真是有耐心啊
You are so patient with her.
你是如何做到的?
How do you do it?
作为蓝宝石,我知道这肯定会发生的
As a Sapphire, I know it will happen eventually.
就这样吧
That will be all.
对不起
Sorry.
坚持一下
Hang in there.
跟上啊,珍珠
Do keep up, Pearl.
这个设施的下半部分
The bottom half of this structure
完全关注于物种保存
is devoted entirely to specimen containment.
显然,人类不愿意被拘禁
Apparently, humans don't take well to captivity.
但只要你了解他们的需求
But once you understand their needs,
他们很容易控制
they're easy to control.
这真是个悲剧-粉钻在宇宙中的存在
It's tragic that Pink Diamond's existence in this universe
居然如此有限
ended up being so finite.
但蓝钻的表现是如此无私,
But what a selfless act for Blue Diamond
愿意站出来花费自己的时间与精力
to step forward and spend her own time and energy
保存这个地方-只为纪念粉钻石
preserving this place in Pink Diamond's memory.
这是蓝钻石仁慈与友爱
It's a real testament to Blue Diamond's merciful
真正的纪念碑,你不觉得吗?
and giving nature, don't you think?
呃,当然
Uh, of course.
坚持住,红宝石,我们的角色,记得吗?
Hold it together, Ruby. Our roles, remember?
然后走这里,是健康保留分区
And pass this way, the health reservation sector,
一定要"艾斯呆板"住啊
Gotta Esteban it.
而这里,显然,是人类处理滑槽
And here, of course, is the human disposal chute.
什-
Wha--
如-如何进入动物园?
H-How do get in the zoo?
哦,又是那滑稽的噪音
Oh, there it goes again with its hilarious noises.
那么,你是如何进入动物园的?
So, how do you get in the zoo?
非常好的问题,伟大的壁下
Excellent question, Your Grand Clarity.
在一些特别情况下
On the rare occasion that we would need
我们进入收容区域
to enter the containment area,
要通过这个维护大门
we would do so via this service door.
爸爸,这个门是我们找到爸爸的关键
Dad. That door's how we get to Dad.
我们只需要分散一下注意力
We just need to come up with a distraction.
好的!
Got it!
作为单向接入点,这里并没有发生逃脱的可能性
As one-way access point, there are no risks of an escape.
实际上,只有一次这里被用于一个人类-
In fact, it's only been used once for a human --
爆炸!
Explosion!
对不起?
Pardon me?
呃...
Uh.
我刚想起来我忘了关掉引力引擎了
I just remembered I left the gravity engine idling.
对不起,蓝宝石,我真是健忘和廉价啊
Sorry, my Sapphire, I'm so forgetful and disposable.
这?
What?
...是一个我预见到的事件
...a foreseen turn of events.
是的,它将会过热并爆炸
Yes, it is going to overheat and explode.
破坏会非常巨大
The damage will be massive.
我的言辞啊!
My word!
我不知道为什么有人会将宇宙飞船托付给红宝石
I don't know why anyone trusts Rubies with those ships.
这就是后果
This is what happens.
如果我们抓紧,我们能关掉引擎
If we hurry, we can disable the engine
避免任何破坏
before any damage is done.
我应该只要五分钟
I should only take five minutes,
所以每个人要做到行为规矩
so everyone be on your best behavior.
嗯?
Hm?
噢!
Oh.
来这里,璧下
This way, Your Clarity.
虽然,我确定你不需要我的指引
Although, I'm sure you don't need my guidance.
啊!
Argh!
我才不信
I can't believe all that stuff
蓝宝石有那么仁慈!
about Blue Diamond being merciful!
她会粉碎宝石啊!
She's a shatterer!
她对蓝宝石大喊大叫!她憎恨融合!
She yelled at Sapphire! She hates Fusion!
还有爱!
And love!
我知道,红宝石,但我们并没有多少时间了!
I know, Ruby, but we don't have much time!
我们得打开这道门!
We have to open this door!
好,好
Right, right.
珍珠,开门!
Pearl, open it!
当然,我还会做什么?
Of course. What else am I good for?
这个和其他的不一样
It's different than the other ones.
啊哈!
Aha!
我其实根本理解不了这个
I actually can't figure this out at all.
什么?!
What?!
但珍珠,你是团队里的骇客
But Pearl, you're our hacker.
我们没那么多时间!
We don't have time for this!
史蒂文,帮我打开门!
Steven, help me open the door!
好的
Okay.
还有,珍珠,骇得快点!
And Pearl, hack faster!
我很高兴我们马上就回来了!
I am so glad we're almost back!
我真的很享受这次行程!
I was really enjoying the tour!
使得,我能从你的声音里听出来
Yes, I can tell by the tone of your voice.
再次感谢你避免了这次危机
Thank you so much again for averting that crisis.
发生了什么?
What is going on?
哦,呃,我确定这有合理的解释-
Oh, well, I'm sure there's a reasonable --
你们看到是哪个紫晶做的吗?
Did you see the Amethyst that did this?
我们可是有客人
Really, we have guests.
霍利蓝玛瑙-我们有非常重要的消息给你!
Holly Blue Agate, - We have important news for you!
我们在这些走廊中不能跑动或喧哗!
We do not run or shout in these hallways!
我对不起,只-只是-
I'm sorry, i-it's just that --
我怎么听出来你要说什么,
How am I supposed to know what you're saying
像你这样含混的话?
when you're mumbling?
呃,对不起,霍利蓝玛瑙,只是-
Uh, I'm sorry, Holly Blue Agate, it's just --
蓝钻石要来这里!
Blue Diamond is on her way!
哦 ,我的星星啊!她这就回来了?
Oh, my stars! She's back already?
你们两个,注意举止!
You two, best behavior!
肩膀要平!
Shoulders squared!
头脑专注!
Minds cleared!
站直了!
Backs straight!
而且,蓝钻石
And surely, Blue Diamond
肯定想亲自对您表达谢意
will want to thank you personally
非常感谢您的特别货物,伟大的璧下
for this special delivery, Your Grand Clarity.
是的,我觉得她会的
Yes, I suppose she will.
那么别傻站在这里,你们这群没用的土包子,
Well don't just stand there, you useless chunks of earth,
做点实事,护送那个人类
make yourself useful and escort that human
到同化隔间!
to the assimilation bay!
但是行程
But the tour.
哦,璧下,您真是太抬举我了
Oh, Your Clarity, you flatter me.
但我们真的必须得做好准备了
But we really must get ready.
我们的钻石随时都会到达!
Our Diamond will be here at any moment!
放开我,你们这群大号的紫晶!
Let me go, you bigger Amethyst!
哈,这些新鲜的人类真是胆肥啊
Ha. These newer humans are so spunky.
进去吧!
In you go!
这是-
What the --
呃...
Uh...
嘿!
Hey!
不!
Nope!
我自己会脱
I can do that myself.
看样子只能光着身子找爸爸了
I'll just find my dad without pants.
兜裆布
Loin cloths.
好吧,还有什么?你们还想从我这里得到什么?
Okay, what else, huh? What else you got for me?
我现在处于老爸任务的肾上腺素模式
I'm on that dad-mission adrenalin rush
随时准备着对付你们接下来的太空狗屁呢
and ready for whatever space junk you have next.
高科技赶牛棒,人用马掌-
Futuristic cattle prods, human horseshoes --
随便你,来对付我啊!
whatever you got, come and get me!
呃?
Huh?
什么-
What the --
这是哪里?
What is this place?
而-而且爸爸在...
A-And where's...
这儿?
Dad?